<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News | Trisha Gopalakrishna</title>
    <link>/news/</link>
      <atom:link href="/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>News</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>/news/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2019</title>
      <link>/news/summer2019/summer-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/news/summer2019/summer-2019/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/news/summer2019/2019-07-30-summer-2019_files/Screen%20Shot%202019-07-29%20at%204.20.17%20PM.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been accepted into the DPhil Geography and the Environment program at the University of Oxford, UK. I will be advised by Dr. Yadvinder Malhi and my proposed research is prioritization of restoration methodologies in tropical forest systems by understanding the tradeoffs and synergies between climate change mitigation, water provision and biodiversity value, under future climate change scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/news/summer2019/2019-07-30-summer-2019_files/Screen%20Shot%202019-07-30%20at%204.25.37%20PM.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I am the Oxford Indira Gandhi 2019 Scholar at the Oxford India Center for Sustainable Development, Somerville College, University of Oxford. I am very thankful for this prestigious fellowship!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2016</title>
      <link>/news/summer2016/summer-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/news/summer2016/summer-2016/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will be moving to Arlington, VA to start a science internship with the Center for Sustanability Science, The Nature Conservancy! I will be involved in two projects- understanding knowledge diffusion/sharing within and beyond TNC being the first and estimating aboveground live grassland biomass in the southern Andean mountains of Peru.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/news/summer2016/2019-07-30-summer-2016_files/tnclogo.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I graduated with a Master of Environmental Management, Ecosystem Science and Conservation concentration! I also managed to earn the GIS certificate. I am so happy that I went to Duke and graduated!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2016</title>
      <link>/news/spring2016/spring-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/news/spring2016/spring-2016/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been awarded another graduate teaching assistantship under John Fay to assist the Geospatial Analysis for Conservation &amp;amp; Management graduate course. Yet another chance to reinforce my GIS skills and communicate with students!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I presented my Master’s Project on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dukespace.lib.duke.edu/dspace/handle/10161/52/browse?value=Gopalakrishna%2C+Trisha&amp;amp;type=author&#34;&gt;Constituents and drivers of composition, diversity and structure of a Congolese forest&lt;/a&gt; at the Nicholas School of the Environment Master’s Project Symposium (April 2016).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2015</title>
      <link>/news/fall2015/fall-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/news/fall2015/fall-2015/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I presented a speed talk titled “Conservation &amp;amp; Management in the Tropics” at the Duke University Joint Ecology/Marine Symposium on November 13th,14th 2015 at the Duke Marine Lab, Beaufort, NC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I presented a poster titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1DJFW_oTYVmScJJEf4tIAd4WnAdMhqYOU/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;“Do plants have enemies? Their effects on plant recruitment in an Afrotropical forest system”&lt;/a&gt; at the Student Conference on Conservation Science, New York 2015. This was a great opportunity to show case my work to a wide audience working towards conservation in so many different parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been awarded one of four teaching assistantship for the Fundamental of GIS graduate level course under Dr. Patrick Halpin &amp;amp; Dr. Peter Harrell. I am looking forward to this opportunity to engage students and strengthen my geospatial skill set!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2015</title>
      <link>/news/summer2015/summer-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/news/summer2015/summer-2015/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/news/summer2015/2019-07-30-summer-2015_files/chameleon.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I returned to pursue my 2nd year of Master’s at Duke after an eventful summer at Ipassa Research Station, Ivindo National Park, Gabon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was awarded the IDEAWILD Equipment Grant for my fieldwork over the summer. Woot!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/news/summer2015/2019-07-30-summer-2015_files/ideawild.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have been nominated as an Associate Member to the Sigma- Xi society in recognition of my potential as an outstanding career researcher. This will be a great opportunity and I look forward to it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2015</title>
      <link>/news/spring2015/spring-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/news/spring2015/spring-2015/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am the proud recipient of the Kuzmier- Lee- Nikitine Endowment Fund 2015 that is supporting my work this summer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am happy to announce that I am a recipient of the Nicholas School of the Environment International Internship Grant that will support my research in Gabon over the summer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2014</title>
      <link>/news/fall2014/fall2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/news/fall2014/fall2014/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;I appreciate and express my gratitude to the Nicholas School of the Environment for awarding me an academic scholarship for the Master’s of Environmental Management program at Duke University.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
